<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Label/title of event</title>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Entry created by: </resp><persName>Author name</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Entry created for: </resp><name>Digital Diversity 2015</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName>Canadian Writing Research Collaboratory</orgName>
                </publisher>
                <availability>
                    <p>Use of this public-domain resource is governed by the <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>No source; originally written in digital form.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng"><note type="researchNote">Please change the ident attribute of the language tag using the language codes in the <ref target="http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/php/English_list.php">ISO 639-2 specification (http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/php/English_list.php)</ref>, if the language of the event is not English. Some of the most common languages: chi (Chinese languages), spa (Spanish), hin (Hindi), ara (Arabic), por (Portuguese).</note></language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <note type="researchNote">Please edit the header of this document. Click on the "Edit header" button at the top-right of the CWRC Writer window.</note>
            <note type="researchNote">Please fill in the type attribute value for the event element below: bibliographical, biographical, cultural, literary, political, or social.</note>
            <listEvent>
                <event type="biographical">
                    <label>Label/title of the event</label>
                    <desc>Date, place.</desc>
                    <desc>Description of the event (optional)</desc>
                    <note type="researchNote">Fill in the date and location of the event inside the first description tag. Format as "Date, place" and tag as such using the "Tag Date" and "Tag Place" buttons on the ribon above. To identify the place, use the VIAF lookup primarely. If the location cannot be found there, use the Geocode or the CWRC lookups.</note>
                    <note type="researchNote">Use multiple description tags for a multi-paragraph extended description.</note>
                    <note type="scholarNote">Scholar note <note type="researchNote">optional - delete if none.</note></note>
                    <listBibl>
                        <bibl>Source of event description and/or note <note type="researchNote">optional - delete list bibl if none; multiple sources-separate bibl tags; Use the "tag title" button to link the referenced resource to a title in the CWRC repository or the VIAF service.</note></bibl>
                    </listBibl>
                    <note type="keyword"><term></term><note type="researchNote">To make the event more discoverable, please add at least one keyword; to add more than one keyword, additional term elements (separated by commas) should be created for each additional keyword.</note></note>
                </event>
            </listEvent>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
