<?xml-model href="http://cwrc.ca/schemas/cwrc_tei_lite.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://cwrc.ca/templates/css/digital_diversity.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Label/title of event</title>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Entry created by:</resp>
                    <persName>Author name</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Entry created for:</resp>
                    <name>Digital Diversity 2015</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName>Canadian Writing Research Collaboratory</orgName>
                </publisher>
                <availability>
                    <p>Use of this public-domain resource is governed by the <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>No source; originally written in digital form.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident=""/>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <note type="researchNote">Please fill in the ident attribute of the language tag in the header using the language codes in the <ref target="http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/php/English_list.php">ISO 639-2 specification</ref>. Please fill in the type attribute value for the event element: bibliographical, biographical, cultural, literary, political, or social.</note>
            <listEvent>
                <event type="biographical">
                    <label>Label/title of the event</label>
                    <desc><date when="2010">Date or date-range of the event <note type="researchNote">Please fill in the "when" attribute values for single dates or the "from" and "to" attributes for date ranges. Attribute values consisting of dates must be formatted as: YYYY, YYYY-MM, or YYYY-MM-DD. (e.g., 2010, 2010-10, 2010-10-31) </note></date>, <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/---------/">location of the event <note type="researchNote">Please look up the GeoNames entry of your location at <ref target="http://www.geonames.org/">http://www.geonames.org/</ref>. Select it from the list of results. On the resulting map, you will most likely be told that there are multiple results in the area. Click on this notice. Out of the resulting list, select the appropriate entry, usually the first or second entry. Once you click on it, you will see a numerical id at the top-right coner of the resulting popup.Copy it and paste it in the value of the ref attribute to replace the dotted line. (e.g., the ref attribute value for Edmonton is "http://www.geonames.org/5946768/")</note></placeName></desc>
                    <desc>Description of the event (optional)</desc>
                    <note type="researchNote">Use multiple description tags for a multi-paragraph description.</note>
                    <note type="scholarNote">Scholar note <note type="researchNote">optional - delete if none.</note></note>
                    <listBibl>
                        <bibl>Source of event description and/or note <note type="researchNote">optional - delete list bibl if none; multiple sources-separate bibl tags</note></bibl>
                    </listBibl>
                </event>
            </listEvent>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
