<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://cwrc.ca/schemas/orlando_entry.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/orlando.css"?>
<ENTRY ID="SixLetterCode" PERSON="BRWWRITER" SEX="FEMALE">
    <ORLANDOHEADER>
        <FILEDESC>
            <TITLESTMT>
                <DOCTITLE>[Insert Author Name]</DOCTITLE>
            </TITLESTMT>
            <PUBLICATIONSTMT>
                <AUTHORITY>Orlando Project</AUTHORITY>
            </PUBLICATIONSTMT>
            <SOURCEDESC>Created from original research by members of the Orlando
                Project</SOURCEDESC>
        </FILEDESC>
        <XENODATA>
            <RDF xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"/>
        </XENODATA>
    </ORLANDOHEADER>
    <DIV0>
        <STANDARD>[InsertAuthorStandardName]</STANDARD>
        <AUTHORSUMMARY>
            <RESEARCHNOTE>This subsection (AUTHORSUMMARY) usually encloses summary statements about
                an author (a short preface) which are visible before opening the writing document of
                each woman writer. This element can contain a short writer profile, or an entry
                summary (similar to an abstract). It is useful both for minor writers about whom
                little is known, and for major writers whose work needs to be summarized before
                launching into the details. In results on a tag search, access to the AuthorSummary
                appears as Profile; users click on it for a thumbnail on authors appearing in their
                results. For this reason it should be kept short (ideally not more than five lines)
                but should usually specify time-period and most important genres written, and should
                indicate what is interesting in this writer.</RESEARCHNOTE>
            <P>[Insert author summary here]</P>
        </AUTHORSUMMARY>
        <BIOGRAPHY>
            <RESEARCHNOTE>This template provides sections for topics generally found in a writer's
                entry. Please note that any irrelevant tags or sections can simply be deleted when
                not applicable. You can also add other sections, with other available tags (see
                below) like INTIMATERELATIONSHIPS (non-familial intimate relationships; this tag has
                an attribute), FRIENDSASSOCIATES (close, and broader social circle), HEALTH (mental
                and physical health, including issues having to do with the female body; this tag
                has an attribute), LOCATION (travel, visits, moves, migrations, and residences; this
                tag has an attribute), POLITICS (political affiliations and degree of involvement in
                political organizations), LEISUREANDSOCIETY (social and leisure activities),
                VIOLENCE (any domestic or other violence), WEALTH (material wealth or poverty;
                significant changes in standard of living). N.b. insert a Chronstruct wherever you
                wish information to be tied to a date, available for pulling out into timelines (as
                in Birth and Death here. When in doubt over decisions, try looking at existing
                Orlando entries.</RESEARCHNOTE>
            <HEADING>Biography</HEADING>
            <DIV1>
                <PERSONNAME>
                    <DIV2>
                        <DATASTRUCT>
                            <RESEARCHNOTE>Only a few names types will apply in each entry. Delete
                                all name types that do not apply (including their enclosing DATAITEM
                                tags)</RESEARCHNOTE>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <BIRTHNAME>
                                    <GIVEN>[BirthGivenName]</GIVEN>
                                    <GIVEN>[BirthGivenName]</GIVEN>
                                    <SURNAME>[BirthSurname]</SURNAME>
                                </BIRTHNAME>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <NICKNAME>[InsertNickname]</NICKNAME>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <MARRIED>[InsertMarriedName]</MARRIED>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <INDEXED>[InsertIndexedName]</INDEXED>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <SELFCONSTRUCTED>[InsertSelfConsctructedName]</SELFCONSTRUCTED>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <PSEUDONYM>[InsertPseudonym]</PSEUDONYM>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <RELIGIOUSNAME>[InsertReligiousName]</RELIGIOUSNAME>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <ROYAL>[InsertRoyalName]</ROYAL>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <STYLED>[InsertStyledName]</STYLED><RESEARCHNOTE>This is for what
                                    are called courtesy titles, e.g. Lady Mary (as opposed to Lady
                                    Smith, which is Titled). Don&apos;t worry about
                                    it!</RESEARCHNOTE>
                            </DATAITEM>
                            <DATAITEM>
                                <TITLED>[InsertTitledName]</TITLED>
                            </DATAITEM>
                        </DATASTRUCT>
                    </DIV2>
                </PERSONNAME>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <HEADING>Birth and Family</HEADING>
                <BIRTH>
                    <DIV2>
                        <CHRONSTRUCT RESP="SYS" RELEVANCE="SELECTIVE" CHRONCOLUMN="WRITINGCLIMATE">
                            <DATE>[Insert date]</DATE>
                            <CHRONPROSE><BIRTHPOSITION>[Insert prose statement about birth here:
                                    place, birth position if known, any other relevant detail.
                                    Delete Birthposition tag if this is not
                                known.]</BIRTHPOSITION></CHRONPROSE>
                            <BIBCITS>
                                <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT>
                            </BIBCITS>
                        </CHRONSTRUCT>
                        <RESEARCHNOTE>Above is an empty bibliographical citation (BIBCIT tag):
                            please fill in the appropriate information, plus both the PLACEHOLDER,
                            and the DBREF attributes. Note that the plural BIBCITS tag is used to
                            enclose one or any number of BIBCIT tags. Please insert at least one
                            BIBCIT at the end of each paragraph or CHRONSTRUCT.</RESEARCHNOTE>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert any further details of birth here. Delete tags if nothing
                                further to add.] <BIBCITS>
                                    <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT>
                                </BIBCITS></P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </BIRTH>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <CULTURALFORMATION>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert prose summary here of issues and circumstances surrounding
                                class, language, religion, sexuality, race, ethnicity, nationality,
                                and geographical heritage. This tag should always be used even if
                                all you have little to say, e.g. that she was a middle-class
                                Englishwoman, Methodist, presumably white. If you want to enter into
                                detail about any of these issues, do so in a second-level DIV2 tag
                                within CulturalFormation (see list in About the Tags), e.g.
                                &lt;culturalformation>&lt;religion>&lt;div2>&lt;shortprose>&lt;p>[prose
                                description of sect or personal beliefs
                                here]&lt;/>&lt;/>&lt;/>&lt;/>,&lt;/>. One example follows.</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                    <RELIGION>
                        <DIV2>
                            <SHORTPROSE>
                                <P>[Insert information here if, for instance, she later diverged
                                    sharply from the religion of her upbringing. Tag e.g. Anglican
                                    Church with both &lt;denomination> and &lt;orgname> tags.]</P>
                            </SHORTPROSE>
                        </DIV2>
                    </RELIGION>
                </CULTURALFORMATION>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <FAMILY>
                    <MEMBER RELATION="MOTHER">
                        <DIV2>
                            <HEADING>Mother</HEADING>
                            <SHORTPROSE>
                                <P>[Insert prose here: a paragraph or two if you have pertinent
                                    information, but always in sentence form even if you have
                                    nothing but a birth name.]</P>
                            </SHORTPROSE>
                        </DIV2>
                    </MEMBER>
                    <MEMBER RELATION="FATHER">
                        <DIV2>
                            <HEADING>Father</HEADING>
                            <SHORTPROSE>
                                <P>[Insert prose here]</P>
                            </SHORTPROSE>
                        </DIV2>
                    </MEMBER>
                    <MEMBER RELATION="OTHER">
                        <DIV2>
                            <SHORTPROSE>
                                <P>[Insert prose here and in parallel div2s about any siblings,
                                    grandparents, aunts etc. who call for comment. Alter attribute
                                    according to relation. Copy and repeat as necessary; add
                                    Heading(s) to taste; delete this Member tag if nothing to say
                                    about family members except parents. You can insert a &lt;div2>
                                    immediately inside the &lt;family> tag (without using
                                    &lt;member> for general statements about the family.]</P>
                            </SHORTPROSE>
                        </DIV2>
                    </MEMBER>
                </FAMILY>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <HEADING>Education</HEADING>
                <RESEARCHNOTE>Please click on the EDUCATION element below, and add the appropriate
                    MODE attribute value (see attribute panel after clicking on
                    EDUCATION)</RESEARCHNOTE>
                <EDUCATION>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert prose here. You may want to add another Education tag to
                                recognize two MODE attributes, e.g. one for Institutional and one
                                for Self-taught. Remember there are specific tags for subjects
                                studied, school companions, instructors, degrees, awards, and
                                contested behaviour (rebellion, nonconformity, etc.). Remember also
                                to use a chronstruct wherever you want to tie a statement to a date.<BIBCITS>
                                    <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT>
                                </BIBCITS>]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </EDUCATION>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <LOCATION RELATIONTO="LIVED">
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[You will likely want to say where she grew up. This Location tag may
                                be used to capture information about later places connected with
                                her, or you may prefer to open another one(s) later. You may use it,
                                too, with different attributes for visiting, travelling, etc. Delete
                                this tag if nothing to say on this subject.]<BIBCITS>
                                    <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT>
                                </BIBCITS></P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </LOCATION>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <HEADING>Marriage</HEADING>
                <RESEARCHNOTE>Please click on the MEMBER element below, and add the appropriate
                    RELATION attribute value (currently set to "HUSBAND"). Delete complete DIV1 if
                    not applicable.)</RESEARCHNOTE>
                <FAMILY>
                    <MEMBER RELATION="HUSBAND">
                        <MARRIAGE>
                            <DIV2>
                                <CHRONSTRUCT CHRONCOLUMN="BRITISHWOMENWRITERS"
                                    RELEVANCE="COMPREHENSIVE" RESP="IMG">
                                    <DATE/>
                                    <CHRONPROSE>[Wedding date is a milestone worth mentioning if
                                        known. If you can&apos;t or don&apos;t want to give it,
                                        delete Chronstruct. <RESEARCHNOTE>n.b. choosing a Relevance
                                            attribute is a judgement call. Most events in bio
                                            documents are Comprehensive (furthest from Selective)
                                            because they are not significant to literary history,
                                            only to the subject herself.</RESEARCHNOTE></CHRONPROSE>
                                    <BIBCITS>
                                        <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT>
                                    </BIBCITS>
                                </CHRONSTRUCT>
                                <SHORTPROSE>
                                    <P>[Insert prose here about either the spouse, the marriage, or
                                        both. You may want to place information about children here
                                        (inside &lt;children> tag with attribute giving number;
                                        still births etc. are counted in if recorded). Or you may
                                        want a separate &lt;member> tag for a child whose life or
                                        career is of interest.]</P>
                                </SHORTPROSE>
                            </DIV2>
                        </MARRIAGE>
                    </MEMBER>
                    <MEMBER RELATION="CHILD">
                        <DIV2>
                            <SHORTPROSE>
                                <P>[This is another member tag for a child. Change the attribute on
                                    the member tag if you want to specify a daughter, son, or
                                    another relation.</P>
                            </SHORTPROSE>
                        </DIV2>
                    </MEMBER>
                </FAMILY>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <HEADING>Occupation</HEADING>
                <OCCUPATION>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert prose here: anything about a writer&apos;s day job or other
                                important activities. Choose different words for &lt;heading> if
                                appropriate. Use &lt;job> for paid work and &lt;significantactivity>
                                for something major but unpaid. Delete the tag if nothing to say
                                about work.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </OCCUPATION>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <POLITICS>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert any statement about political activity, using
                                &lt;politicalaffiliation> tag if appropriate. Orlando defines
                                political activity broadly, encompassing activism around
                                vegetarianism, homelessness, etc. &lt;Liveswith> tag is available
                                here. Use &lt;heading> if you wish and include citation.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </POLITICS>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <FRIENDSASSOCIATES>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert comment on friendships, joint action, enmities etc. Tag
                                names; use &lt;heading> if you wish, include citation.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </FRIENDSASSOCIATES>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <INTIMATERELATIONSHIPS>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Remember this tag covers more than only sexual relations (see
                                attribute). Occasionally family or business relationships may
                                qualify. &lt;Liveswith> tag is available here.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </INTIMATERELATIONSHIPS>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <WEALTH>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert any information about non-literary earnings, family money,
                                extraordinary expenses, etc. This tag seems to capture more about
                                poverty than about wealth.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </WEALTH>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <HEALTH>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Use this for significant rather than day-to-day information;
                                don&apos;t get overwhelmed in detail.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </HEALTH>
            </DIV1>
            <RESEARCHNOTE>n.b. there are still more big-bucket tags available - &lt;violence>, used
                both for e.g. marital violence and for e.g. bombing in wartime,
                &lt;leisureandsociety>, and &lt;otherlifeevent> - for which the procedure is as
                above. Delete the Div1 below (&lt;Death>) if subject still alive.</RESEARCHNOTE>
            <DIV1>
                <HEADING>Death</HEADING>
                <DEATH>
                    <DIV2>
                        <CHRONSTRUCT RESP="SYS" RELEVANCE="SELECTIVE" CHRONCOLUMN="WRITINGCLIMATE">
                            <DATE>[InsertDate]</DATE>
                            <CHRONPROSE>[Insert summary of event here, including place and cause
                                (for which there is a tag) if known]</CHRONPROSE>
                            <BIBCITS>
                                <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT>
                            </BIBCITS>
                        </CHRONSTRUCT>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert details of event here]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </DEATH>
            </DIV1>
        </BIOGRAPHY>
        <WRITING>
            <HEADING>Writing</HEADING>
            <DIV1>
                <HEADING>[Insert first heading: could be Novels, or Before her First Travels, or
                    Left Unpublished, depending on how you decide to organize the
                    document.]</HEADING>
                <DIV2>
                    <HEADING>Insert first subheading if you wish. If you are going to comment on a
                        string of works, you may want a new div2 for each, whose subheadings are all
                        titles. If you&apos;re giving just 2 paragraphs to her novels, grouping them
                        all together, you probably don&apos;t want any subheading at all.</HEADING>
                    <RESEARCHNOTE>If it&apos;s one div2 per text, then you need a bibliography entry
                        for each, and a Textscope tag (which goes, as here, inside the div2 tag,
                        after the heading). A textscope has no <SOCALLED>prose</SOCALLED>, only the
                        attribute values filled in for dbref and placeholder. The first is the bibl
                        dbase number, the latter lists author, Reg title, and date, e.g. Jane
                        Austen, Pride and Prejudice, 1813. The textscope exists to link all
                        citations of a primary text to the core discussion of it. Before making any
                        new entry in the bibliography database, check to see if this text (in this
                        edition) is already listed there; if so, use the existing bibl dbase
                        number.</RESEARCHNOTE>
                    <TEXTSCOPE> </TEXTSCOPE>
                    <PRODUCTION>
                        <RESEARCHNOTE>PRODUCTION : In this section you can supply basic facts about
                            composition and publication. You can also as far as you wish expand on
                            literary activity related to the work or group of works in question,
                            writing influences, literary schools, material conditions of writing,
                            authorship issues, relationships with publishers, rejections, earnings,
                            editions, mode of publication, type of press, place of publication,
                            price, editions, periodical publication, circulation, press run,
                            advertising, anthologization, media, manuscript history, current
                            archival locations, etc.</RESEARCHNOTE>
                        <CHRONSTRUCT CHRONCOLUMN="WRITINGCLIMATE" RELEVANCE="SELECTIVE" RESP="SYS">
                            <DATE>DD Month YYYY</DATE>
                            <CHRONPROSE>[Insert brief (ideally not more than two lines) statement as
                                to composition (if this is dated) or publication. Include title of
                                work and if possible name and tag its genre(s). Though you may wish
                                to name publisher and/or place of publication you don&apos;t need
                                to, since this will be available in the bibliographic
                                    listing.]<RESEARCHNOTE>You may not wish to tie any statement
                                    about this text or group of texts to a date (for appearing in
                                    timelines). In that case delete the Chronstruct and position
                                    your comments in Shortprose.</RESEARCHNOTE></CHRONPROSE>
                            <BIBCITS>
                                <BIBCIT>
                                    <RESEARCHNOTE>You need a citation for specific facts (see Life
                                        template).</RESEARCHNOTE>
                                </BIBCIT>
                            </BIBCITS>
                        </CHRONSTRUCT>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Add more details, as above, about this text and its
                                    making.]<RESEARCHNOTE>As in everything else, your best guide is
                                    to look at existing Orlando entries and see how they are
                                    structured.</RESEARCHNOTE><BIBCITS>
                                    <BIBCIT/>
                                </BIBCITS></P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </PRODUCTION>
                    <TEXTUALFEATURES>
                        <RESEARCHNOTE>TEXTUALFEATURES: Descriptions or summaries of plot, setting,
                            genre names, tone/style, voice/narration, literary techniques,
                            theme/topic, motifs, characters, intertextuality:anything you want to
                            say about this text(s).</RESEARCHNOTE>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Textual features prose here]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </TEXTUALFEATURES>
                    <RECEPTION>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <RESEARCHNOTE>RECEPTION: Responses to his/her work: reviews,
                                self-description, fictionalized treatments of the author,
                                recognitions with name and value where appropriate, penalties,
                                destruction of work, influence exerted, best known work, status as
                                landmark text (if any, and if not said in publication Chronstruct).
                                N.b. responses to a specific work are best discussed in its div2;
                                reponses to a writer&apos;s oeuvre are best kept for separate
                                Reception tag late in the entry.</RESEARCHNOTE>
                            <P>[Reception prose here]<BIBCITS>
                                    <BIBCIT/>
                                </BIBCITS></P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </RECEPTION>
                </DIV2>
            </DIV1>
            <DIV1>
                <HEADING>Insert second heading: could be Poetry, or After Visiting Asia, or In
                    Periodicals, etc.</HEADING>
                <RESEARCHNOTE>To create more sections or subsections, EITHER copy this entire DIV1
                    and paste below, after the div1 ends and before the WORKSCITED tag, OR copy the
                    div2 that follows and paste it after the div2 ends but before the div1 ends. You
                    may need to do this several times or many times. Do it BEFORE you begin writing
                    within the existing div1 or div2.</RESEARCHNOTE>
                <DIV2>
                    <HEADING>Insert subheading if desired.</HEADING>
                    <TEXTSCOPE/>
                    <PRODUCTION>
                        <CHRONSTRUCT CHRONCOLUMN="WRITINGCLIMATE" RELEVANCE="SELECTIVE" RESP="SYS">
                            <DATE>DD Month YYYY</DATE>
                            <CHRONPROSE>[Event Prose: anything that needs to be tied to a date, like
                                composition, submission/rejection, publication.</CHRONPROSE>
                            <BIBCITS>
                                <BIBCIT/>
                            </BIBCITS>
                        </CHRONSTRUCT>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[further details of composition and publication ]<BIBCITS>
                                    <BIBCIT/>
                                </BIBCITS></P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </PRODUCTION>
                    <TEXTUALFEATURES>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Textual features prose here]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </TEXTUALFEATURES>
                    <RECEPTION>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Reception prose here]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </RECEPTION>
                </DIV2>
            </DIV1>
            <RESEARCHNOTE>You may wish to close with a
                &lt;div1>&lt;div2>&lt;production>&lt;shortprose>&lt;p> containing a general
                statement about e.g. editions or translations or illustration or performance, or
                about whereabouts of archives. And/or with parallel &lt;textualfeatures> or
                &lt;reception> sections about general characteristics of her oeuvre, and/or about
                initial success and later attack, or vice versa, or reputation generally. You may or
                may not wish to give such a paragraph or paragraphs a Heading. Don&apos;t forget to
                compare with some existing Orlando entries!</RESEARCHNOTE>
        </WRITING>
        <WORKSCITED>
            <SOURCE> Unless otherwise noted, all information is from <TITLE TITLETYPE="MONOGRAPHIC"
                    >[InsertSourceTitle]</TITLE>. </SOURCE>
            <SOURCE>[InsertWorkCited]</SOURCE>
            <RESEARCHNOTE>You may find it useful to insert here details of sources you have used, if
                for instance someone else, not yourself, is going to enter them in the bibl
                dbase.</RESEARCHNOTE>

        </WORKSCITED>
    </DIV0>
</ENTRY>
