<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://cwrc.ca/schemas/orlando_biography_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/orlando.css"?>

<BIOGRAPHY PERSON="BRWWRITER" SEX="FEMALE">
    <ORLANDOHEADER>
        <FILEDESC>
            <TITLESTMT>
                <DOCTITLE>[Insert Author Name]</DOCTITLE>
            </TITLESTMT>
            <PUBLICATIONSTMT>
                <AUTHORITY>Canadian Writing and Research Collaboratory</AUTHORITY>
            </PUBLICATIONSTMT>
            <SOURCEDESC>Created from original research by members of [insert project name here]</SOURCEDESC>
        </FILEDESC>
        <REVISIONDESC>
            <RESPONSIBILITY RESP="MPO" WORKSTATUS="SUB" WORKVALUE="I">
                <DATE VALUE="2010-09-13">13 September 2010</DATE>
                <ITEM>document template complete</ITEM>
            </RESPONSIBILITY>
        </REVISIONDESC>
    </ORLANDOHEADER>
    <DIV0>
        <RESEARCHNOTE>This template provides sections for topics generally found in a writer's entry. Please note that any irrelevant tags or sections can simply be deleted when not applicable. You can also add other sections, with other available tags (see below) like INTIMATERELATIONSHIPS (non-familial intimate relationships; this tag has an attribute), FRIENDSASSOCIATES (close, and broader social circle), HEALTH (mental and physical health, including issues having to do with the female body; this tag has an attribute), LOCATION (travel, visits, moves, migrations, and residences; this tag has an attribute), POLITICS (political affiliations and degree of involvement in political organizations), LEISUREANDSOCIETY (social and leisure activities), VIOLENCE (any domestic or other violence), WEALTH (material wealth or poverty; significant changes in standard of living). N.b. insert a Chronstruct wherever you wish information to be tied to a date, available for pulling out into timelines (as in Birth and Death here. When in doubt over decisions, try looking at existing Orlando entries.</RESEARCHNOTE>
        <HEADING>Biography</HEADING>
        <STANDARD>[InsertAuthorStandardName]</STANDARD>
        <DIV1>
            <PERSONNAME>
                <DIV2>
                    <DATASTRUCT>
                        <RESEARCHNOTE>Only a few names types will apply in each entry. Delete all name types that do not apply (including their enclosing DATAITEM tags)</RESEARCHNOTE>
                        <DATAITEM> <BIRTHNAME> <GIVEN>[BirthGivenName]</GIVEN> <GIVEN>[BirthGivenName]</GIVEN><SURNAME>[BirthSurname]</SURNAME> </BIRTHNAME> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <NICKNAME>[InsertNickname]</NICKNAME> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <MARRIED>[InsertMarriedName]</MARRIED> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <INDEXED>[InsertIndexedName]</INDEXED> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <SELFCONSTRUCTED>[InsertSelfConsctructedName]</SELFCONSTRUCTED> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <PSEUDONYM>[InsertPseudonym]</PSEUDONYM> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <RELIGIOUSNAME>[InsertReligiousName]</RELIGIOUSNAME> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <ROYAL>[InsertRoyalName]</ROYAL> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <STYLED>[InsertStyledName]</STYLED><RESEARCHNOTE>This is for what are called courtesy titles, e.g. Lady Mary (as opposed to Lady Smith, which is Titled). Don&apos;t worry about it!</RESEARCHNOTE> </DATAITEM>
                        <DATAITEM> <TITLED>[InsertTitledName]</TITLED> </DATAITEM>
                    </DATASTRUCT>
                </DIV2>
            </PERSONNAME>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <HEADING>Birth and Family</HEADING>
            <BIRTH>
                <DIV2>
                    <CHRONSTRUCT RESP="SYS" RELEVANCE="SELECTIVE" CHRONCOLUMN="WRITINGCLIMATE"> <DATE>[Insert date]</DATE> <CHRONPROSE><BIRTHPOSITION>[Insert prose statement about birth here: place, birth position if known, any other relevant detail. Delete Birthposition tag if this is not known.]</BIRTHPOSITION></CHRONPROSE> <BIBCITS> <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT> </BIBCITS></CHRONSTRUCT>
                    <RESEARCHNOTE>Above is an empty bibliographical citation (BIBCIT tag): please fill in the appropriate information, plus both the PLACEHOLDER, and the DBREF attributes. Note that the plural BIBCITS tag is used to enclose one or any number of BIBCIT tags. Please insert at least one BIBCIT at the end of each paragraph or CHRONSTRUCT.</RESEARCHNOTE>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert any further details of birth here. Delete tags if nothing further to add.] <BIBCITS> <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT> </BIBCITS></P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </BIRTH>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <CULTURALFORMATION>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert prose summary here of issues and circumstances surrounding class, language, religion, sexuality, race, ethnicity, nationality, and geographical heritage. This tag should always be used even if all you have little to say, e.g. that she was a middle-class Englishwoman, Methodist, presumably white. If you want to enter into detail about any of these issues, do so in a second-level DIV2 tag within CulturalFormation (see list in About the Tags), e.g. &lt;culturalformation>&lt;religion>&lt;div2>&lt;shortprose>&lt;p>[prose description of sect or personal beliefs here]&lt;/>&lt;/>&lt;/>&lt;/>,&lt;/>. One example follows.</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
                <RELIGION>
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert information here if, for instance, she later diverged sharply from the religion of her upbringing. Tag e.g. Anglican Church with both &lt;denomination> and &lt;orgname> tags.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </RELIGION>
            </CULTURALFORMATION>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <FAMILY>
                <MEMBER RELATION="MOTHER">
                    <DIV2>
                        <HEADING>Mother</HEADING>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert prose here: a paragraph or two if you have pertinent information, but always in sentence form even if you have nothing but a birth name.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </MEMBER>
                <MEMBER RELATION="FATHER">
                    <DIV2>
                        <HEADING>Father</HEADING>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert prose here]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </MEMBER>
                <MEMBER RELATION="OTHER">
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert prose here and in parallel div2s about any siblings, grandparents, aunts etc. who call for comment. Alter attribute according to relation. Copy and repeat as necessary; add Heading(s) to taste; delete this Member tag if nothing to say about family members except parents. You can insert a &lt;div2> immediately inside the &lt;family> tag (without using &lt;member> for general statements about the family.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </MEMBER>
            </FAMILY>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <HEADING>Education</HEADING>
            <RESEARCHNOTE>Please click on the EDUCATION element below, and add the appropriate MODE attribute value (see attribute panel after clicking on EDUCATION)</RESEARCHNOTE>
            <EDUCATION>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert prose here. You may want to add another Education tag to recognize two MODE attributes, e.g. one for Institutional and one for Self-taught. Remember there are specific tags for subjects studied, school companions, instructors, degrees, awards, and contested behaviour (rebellion, nonconformity, etc.). Remember also to use a chronstruct wherever you want to tie a statement to a date.<BIBCITS> <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT> </BIBCITS>]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </EDUCATION>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <LOCATION RELATIONTO="LIVED">
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[You will likely want to say where she grew up. This Location tag may be used to capture information about later places connected with her, or you may prefer to open another one(s) later. You may use it, too, with different attributes for visiting, travelling, etc. Delete this tag if nothing to say on this subject.]<BIBCITS> <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT> </BIBCITS></P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </LOCATION>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <HEADING>Marriage</HEADING>
            <RESEARCHNOTE>Please click on the MEMBER element below, and add the appropriate RELATION attribute value (currently set to "HUSBAND"). Delete complete DIV1 if not applicable.)</RESEARCHNOTE>
            <FAMILY>
                <MEMBER RELATION="HUSBAND">
                    <MARRIAGE> <DIV2>
                        <CHRONSTRUCT CHRONCOLUMN="BRITISHWOMENWRITERS" RELEVANCE="COMPREHENSIVE" RESP="IMG"><DATE></DATE><CHRONPROSE>[Wedding date is a milestone worth mentioning if known. If you can&apos;t or don&apos;t want to give it, delete Chronstruct. <RESEARCHNOTE>n.b. choosing a Relevance attribute is a judgement call. Most events in bio documents are Comprehensive (furthest from Selective) because they are not significant to literary history, only to the subject herself.</RESEARCHNOTE></CHRONPROSE><BIBCITS> <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT> </BIBCITS></CHRONSTRUCT>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[Insert prose here about either the spouse, the marriage, or both. You may want to place information about children here (inside &lt;children> tag with attribute giving number; still births etc. are counted in if recorded). Or you may want a separate &lt;member> tag for a child whose life or career is of interest.]</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                        </DIV2> </MARRIAGE>
                </MEMBER>
                <MEMBER RELATION="CHILD">
                    <DIV2>
                        <SHORTPROSE>
                            <P>[This is another member tag for a child. Change the attribute on the member tag if you want to specify a daughter, son, or another relation.</P>
                        </SHORTPROSE>
                    </DIV2>
                </MEMBER>
            </FAMILY>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <HEADING>Occupation</HEADING>
            <OCCUPATION>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert prose here: anything about a writer&apos;s day job or other important activities. Choose different words for &lt;heading> if appropriate. Use &lt;job> for paid work and &lt;significantactivity> for something major but unpaid. Delete the tag if nothing to say about work.]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </OCCUPATION>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <POLITICS>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert any statement about political activity, using &lt;politicalaffiliation> tag if appropriate. Orlando defines political activity broadly, encompassing activism around vegetarianism, homelessness, etc. &lt;Liveswith> tag is available here. Use &lt;heading> if you wish and include citation.]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </POLITICS>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <FRIENDSASSOCIATES>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert comment on friendships, joint action, enmities etc. Tag names; use &lt;heading> if you wish, include citation.]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </FRIENDSASSOCIATES>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <INTIMATERELATIONSHIPS>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Remember this tag covers more than only sexual relations (see attribute). Occasionally family or business relationships may qualify. &lt;Liveswith> tag is available here.]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </INTIMATERELATIONSHIPS>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <WEALTH>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert any information about non-literary earnings, family money, extraordinary expenses, etc. This tag seems to capture more about poverty than about wealth.]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </WEALTH>
        </DIV1>
        <DIV1>
            <HEALTH>
                <DIV2>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Use this for significant rather than day-to-day information; don&apos;t get overwhelmed in detail.]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </HEALTH>
        </DIV1>
        <RESEARCHNOTE>n.b. there are still more big-bucket tags available - &lt;violence>, used both for e.g. marital violence and for e.g. bombing in wartime, &lt;leisureandsociety>, and &lt;otherlifeevent> - for which the procedure is as above. Delete the Div1 below (&lt;Death>) if subject still alive.</RESEARCHNOTE>
        <DIV1>
            <HEADING>Death</HEADING>
            <DEATH>
                <DIV2>
                    <CHRONSTRUCT RESP="SYS" RELEVANCE="SELECTIVE" CHRONCOLUMN="WRITINGCLIMATE"> <DATE>[InsertDate]</DATE> <CHRONPROSE>[Insert summary of event here, including place and cause (for which there is a tag) if known]</CHRONPROSE><BIBCITS> <BIBCIT>Insert citation information here</BIBCIT> </BIBCITS> </CHRONSTRUCT>
                    <SHORTPROSE>
                        <P>[Insert details of event here]</P>
                    </SHORTPROSE>
                </DIV2>
            </DEATH>
        </DIV1>
        <WORKSCITED>
            <SOURCE> Unless otherwise noted, all information is from <TITLE TITLETYPE="MONOGRAPHIC">[InsertSourceTitle]</TITLE>. </SOURCE>
            <SOURCE>[InsertWorkCited]</SOURCE>
        </WORKSCITED>
    </DIV0>
</BIOGRAPHY>
